Woman's Club of Albany; Records mss139
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1911-2007; 7; 1.91 cubic ft.
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1921-1922 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1922-1923 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1922-1923; 1923-1924 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1923-1924 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1923-1924; 1924-1925 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1924-1925; 1925-1926 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1925-1926; 1926-1927 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1926-1927 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1927-1928 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1928-1929 (Box 1 (7-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Annual Announcement Booklets, 1929-1930 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Monthly News, 1930-1931 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Monthly News, 1932-1933 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Monthly News, 1934-1935 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Monthly News, 1936-1937 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Monthly News, 1938-1939 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Monthly News, 1940-1942 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 7)
  - The Messenger, 1944 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Bound Issues of The Messenger, 1944-1951 (Oversized 6)
  - The Messenger, 1946 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 9)
  - The Messenger, 1947 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 10)
  - The Messenger, 1948 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Draft Copy and Background Material for The Messenger, 1948-1950; Undated (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 12)
  - The Messenger, 1949 (Box 2 (7-Publications), Folder 13)
  - The Messenger, 1950 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 1)
  - The Messenger, 1951 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 2)
  - The Messenger, 1951 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 3)
  - The Messenger, 1952 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 4)
  - The Messenger, 1953 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 5)
  - The Messenger, 1958 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 6)
  - The Messenger, 1959 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 7)
  - The Messenger, 1960 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 8)
  - The Messenger, 1961 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 9)
  - The Messenger, 1962 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 10)
  - The Messenger, 1965 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 11)
  - The Messenger, ca. 1965 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 12)
  - The Messenger, 1966 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 13)
  - The Messenger, 1967 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 14)
  - The Messenger, 1968 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 15)
  - The Messenger, 1970 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 16)
  - The Messenger, 1971 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 17)
  - The Messenger, 1972 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 18)
  - The Messenger, 1973 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 19)
  - The Messenger, 1979 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 20)
  - The Messenger, ca. 1980 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Club and House Rental Information, ca. 1995 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Club Program, 1997-1998 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Club Program, 1998-1999 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Club Informational Packet, 2007 (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 25)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (1 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 26)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (2 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 27)
  - House Rental Informational Pamphlets (3 of 3), Undated (Box 3 (7-Publications), Folder 28)
- Subject Files, 1908-2009; 8; 2.93 cubic ft.
  The Subject Files series contains folders featuring a variety of topics, ranging from photographs of the Clubhouse and members to general correspondence to songs and poems. This series houses materials on the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs and the General Federation of Women's Clubs. It also contains newspaper clippings about the WCA and its members. Many clippings from the early twentieth century mention Mrs. Edward Cameron, who was very involved in the Albany community.
  There is an item in the general correspondence, pre-dating the establishment of the Woman's Club of Albany. A letter to Mrs. Blair about joining the Club is dated 1908, two years before the WCA was founded. It is unclear whether the date is correct.
  The "Exes" File consists of materials related to former Board members. The self-proclaimed "Exes" held an annual event on the anniversary of the WCA's founding.
  - General Correspondence, 1908-2004 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (1 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (2 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Programs and Reports (3 of 3), 1912-1973; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1912-2007; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1913 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Civic and Social Interests, 1913; 1916-1917; 1924; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Program, 1914 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - The Clubhouse, 1914-1987; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1915 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Guest Book, Woman's Club of albany, Inc., 1915-1929 (Oversized 8)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Reports and Programs, 1915-1916; 1922; 1934-1935 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - History of the Club, 1915; 1919; 1940; 1970; 1985 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Homemaking, 1917 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - World War I, 1917 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Period Advertisements Retained by the Club, 1917; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Correspondence and Supplemental Materials, 1917-1988; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings about the Woman's Club of Albany and its Members, 1917; 1925; 1951; 1969; 2007 (Flat-file 1)
  - Letters Pertaining to Stolen Checks, 1918-1919 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - City of Albany, N.Y. Budget, 1919 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Books Retained by Parliamentary Law Committee (1 of 2), 1920 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Books Retained by Parliamentary Law Committee (2 of 2), 1920 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - City Problems, 1922 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - The Albany Mothers' Club, 1922-1923 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - The "Exes" File (1 of 2), 1922-1955; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - The "Exes" File (2 of 2), 1922-1955; Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Albany Public Library, Gifts for Children's Book-Shelves, 1923 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Frame Carved by Alice Pauline Schefer That Held Certificate of Incorporation, 1923 (Flat-file 2)
  - Grace Aguilar Literary Society, 1923 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1923 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Convention Program, 1924 (Oversized 6)
  - New Books Added to the Albany Public Library, 1925-1926 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1927 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Publications on the American Home, 1928; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Songs and Poems Retained by the Club (1 of 2), 1933-1935; 1963-1966; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Songs and Poems Retained by the Club (2 of 2), 1933-1935; 1963-1966; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - New York State Women's Joint Legislative Forum, 1935; 1948; 1960-1965; 1972; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1936-1937 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Mortgage Burning Occasion, 1938 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - United States Constitution Sesquicentennial Commission, 1938 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1938-1939 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Photographs from the Club, 1939-1941 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1942-1943 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1943-1944 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Newsletters and Annual Reports, 1943-1944; 1968-1972; 1988 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Pictures of the Clubhouse, 1944; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Yearbook, 1946-1948 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Clubwoman and Clubwomen's Life magazines, 1947-1948 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Supplemental Roster, 1948 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Unknown Member File from Annual Convention, 1950; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - New York State Federation of Women's Clubs Directory, 1950; 1972; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Third District Meetings, 1951-1970; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - The History of the New York State Federation of Women's Clubs, 1952 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Troy Women's Club Yearbook and Booklet, 1952-1953; 1968-1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Pictures of Club Members, 1955 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs Administration Program, 1958-1962 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Awards Given to the Club, 1960; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Tri-County Meeting Reports, 1960; 1962; 1969; 1971; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - New York State Committee for the Aging Report, 1961 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Historic Albany Foundation, 1968; 2006 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Philanthropic Works, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Pictures of Club Members, 1971-1972; 1995; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Agreement with Residents of the Clubhouse, 1979 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Communications with Caretakers/Residents, 1979; 2001-2003; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Applications for Grants, 1994; 2003-2004 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Photo Negatives of the Clubhouse, 1996 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Articles, 2008 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
  - Clubhouse Restoration, 2008-2009 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Bridge Score Sheets and Playing Cards Featuring Local Businesses, Undated (Oversized 7)
  - Glove Pattern Retained by the Club, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Inventory of Items in Small Drawer, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Photographs Presented to the Woman's Club of Albany by New York State Federation of Women's Clubs, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Pictures of the First Three Presidents and the Clubhouse, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Postcard of the Albany Institute and Historical and Art Society, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Rules and Regulations for Use of Rooms, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)